加州  圣佩德罗-昨晚
你怎么样，基顿？
How you doing, Keaton?
我的双腿没有感觉…
I can't feel my legs...
凯撒
Keyser.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
现在是什么时候了？
What time is it?
12:30.
一切得从六星期前的纽约说起
It all started back in New York six weeks ago.
一辆满载枪械部件的卡车 在皇后区外被劫持了
A truck loaded with stripped gun parts got jacked outside of Queens.
那司机没有看见任何人，但有人搞砸了。
The driver didn't see anyone,but someone fucked up.
他听见一个声音 有时候这就够了
He heard a voice.Sometimes that's all you need.
纽约市(六星期前)
-麦克马纳斯先生？ -神啊！你们这帮烂货从来不睡觉吗？
- Mr.McManus? - Christ! Don't you fucking guys ever sleep?
-我们有你的逮捕令 -草泥马，猪
- We have a warrant for your arrest. - Fuck you, pig.
托德・霍克内
Todd Hockney?
- 是谁找我？  - 纽约警察局
- Who wants to know? - New York Police Department.
- 烂屎 -不许动！
- Shit. - Freeze!
别动！
Hold it!
你们带的人够吗？
Sure you brought enough guys?
这很简单:
It's quite simple:
一家餐厅更换口味，而毫不丧失其整体的艺术感
A restaurant that changes with the taste without losing the overall aesthetic.
换而言之…
In other words...
…气氛并不是靠墙上的粉刷来营造的
...the atmosphere will not be painted on the walls.
- 让我给你举个例子--  - 这我得自己来瞧
- Let me give you an example-- - This I had to see for myself.
戴夫
David.
- 我在会谈  - 该来一场别的会谈了
- I'm in a meeting. - Time for another one.
各位，这位是戴夫・奎恩
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
特别探员奎恩，美国海关
Special Agent Kujan. US Customs.
这几位先生是纽约警局的
These gentlemen are from the New York Police Department.
你气色不错，比我想象的还要好
You look good.Better than I would have thought.
一桩运枪车被偷的小事儿
A small matter of a stolen truck loaded with guns.
基顿先生？
Mr.Keaton?
能原谅我们失陪一会儿吗？
Will you excuse us for a moment?
我们得带你回去问话，你得有一阵子呢
We have some questions to ask you downtown. You'll be a while.
不，请坐下
No. Please, sit down.
这不过是个小问题
This is a small problem.
请慢用.我迟些来跟你们谈
Enjoy the meal. I'll talk to you later.
我出现在那里毫无道理
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
这些家伙都是死硬的劫匪
These guys were hard-core hijackers...
…而我却也在那儿
...but there I was.
不过我当时并不害怕
At that point, I wasn't scared.
我知道自己没干什么，他们不能办我
I knew I hadn't done anything they could do me for.
另外，这挺有意思
Besides, it was fun.
我得把自己装成恶名昭彰的罪犯
I got to make like I was notorious.
你们都知道程序
You all know the drill.
叫到你的号就上前一步，念出给你的话
When your number is called, step forward and repeat the phrase you've been given.
一号，上前
Number 1, step forward.
“钥匙递给我，你他妈的混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
二号，上前
Number 2, step forward.
“把他妈的钥匙给我，你他妈的混账忘八！”
Gimme the fuckin' keys,you fuckin' cocksucker motherfucker!
停，退后.三号上前
Knock it off. Get back.Number 3, step forward.
-“钥匙递给我，混蛋” -请讲英语
- "Hand me the keys, you cocksucker." - In English, please.
-你说什么？ -讲英语
- Excuse me? - In English.
“他妈的钥匙递给我，混蛋” 什么玩意儿？
Hand me the fuckin' keys, you cocksucker.What the fuck?
四号上前
Number 4, step forward.
这是些狗屎，整件事都是陷害
It was bullshit.The whole rap was a setup.
“钥匙递给我，你他妈的混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
这是条子的错
It was the cops' fault.
像这样的人根本不该关在一起
You don't put guys like that into a room together.
谁知道会发生些什么？
Who knows what can happen?
“把钥匙给我，你他妈的混蛋”
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
这事情一定让你们很为难吧
This has really got to be embarrassing for you guys.
他们审了我们整晚上
They drilled us all night.
卡车被劫，有人气疯了， 而条子们却一无所获
Someone was mad about that truck hijacking and the cops had nothing.
他们希望有人会被歪打正着，泄露些什么给他们
They were hoping somebody would slip up and give them something.
他们清楚我们不会反抗，他们知道怎么给我们施压
They knew we wouldn't fight,they knew how to lean on us.
他们一直就是这么干的，我们的权利被抛到九霄云外
They've been doing it forever.Our rights went out the window.
这是种侮辱。可耻。
It was a violation. Disgraceful.
他们先从麦克马纳斯开始。顶尖的“闯门人”
They went after McManus first.Topnotch entry man.
什么卡车？
What truck?
- 运枪的卡车，杂种  - “杂种”？
- The truck with the guns, fucko. - "Fucko"?
他是个好人，虽然疯疯癫癫的
He was a good guy. Crazy, though.
想知道你的伙伴芬斯特跟我们说什么吗？
Wanna know what your pal Fenster told us?
-说谁？ -麦克马纳斯
- Say who? - McManus.
他跟我们说的是另一回事
He told us another story.
是说那个得了痢疾的妓女吗？
Is that the one about the hooker with the dysentery?
芬斯特总是和麦克马纳斯一起干， 他是个真正的小白脸儿
Fenster always worked with McManus.He was a real tight-ass.
但是干起活儿来他不含糊。是个聪明人
But when it came to the job,he was right on. A smart man.
- 你说什么？  - 我说他会教训你的
- What are you saying? - I said he'll flip you.
- 他会什么？ - 教训你.狠狠的教训你
- He'll what? - Flip you. Flip you for real.
- 我在发抖，继续  - 好吧
- I'm shaking. Come on. - Okay.
- 回答我的问题  - 你在后头能听清我吗？
- Answer my questions. - Can you hear me in the back?
喂？
Hello?
我要见律师
I want my lawyer.
我要搞掉你们他妈的警徽，混蛋。
I'm gonna have your fuckin' badge, cocksucker.
托德・霍克内:擅长爆破
Todd Hockney: good with explosives.
毫无疑问，这家伙不买任何人的账
Without a doubt, the one guy who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
你们这些家伙根本他妈的站不住脚
You guys don't have a fuckin' leg to stand on.
你以为是吗，硬汉？
You think so, tough guy?
我能确认劫持发生时你在皇后区。
I can put you in Queens during the hijacking.
真的吗？
Really?
我就住在皇后区
I live in Queens.
这是你自己发现的吗，爱因斯坦？
Did you put that together yourself, Einstein?
你弄了群猴子整天就干这个？
You got a team of monkeys working full time on this?
知道你若是再进联合监狱会怎样吗？
You know what happens if you do another turn in the joint?
我会在淋浴间干你老爸，快进快出
I fuck your father in the shower,and have a snack.
- 你想告我吗，龟头？   - 我准备好了就指控你
- Are you gonna charge me, dickhead? - I'll charge you when I'm ready.
- 告我什么？ - 你很清楚，死人。
- With what? - You know damn well, dead man.
但是基顿？
But Keaton?
显然基顿是他们真正有价值的目标
Keaton was the real prize for them for obvious reasons.
犯错的是你们，不是我
It was your mistake, not mine.
你们问够了没？
Did you ever stop to ask me?
我行不改姓，坐不改名
I've been walking around with the same face, the same name.
我是个商人
I'm a businessman.
做什么生意？餐厅生意？
What's that? The restaurant business?
不，从现在起你的生意就是“被我们搞”
No. From now on you're in the "getting fucked by us" business.
我会让你出名的，混蛋
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
我说过了…
Like I said...
…犯错的是你们
...it was your mistake...
…而不是我
...not mine.
你们要是拿这烂屎来指控我
You charge me with this shit...
…我会反诉你们
...and I'll beat it.
懂吗？
Okay?
继续说卡车的事吧，混蛋
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
真的，该有人管管这烂事了
Really, somebody's got to do something about this shit.
他们动不动就找我麻烦，所以我进去蹲过一小段时间
They put me in holding every five minutes.So I did a little time.
难道说每次有辆卡车不见了 都得把我关进来？
Does that mean I get railed every time a truck finds it's way gone?
操他妈的
Fuck 'em.
芬斯特，放松点好吗？
Fenster, will you relax?
-他们根本没有任何证据 -你他妈说对了，无凭无据
- These guys don't have any probable cause. - You fuckin' right. No PC.
你说的太对了 只要进去过，就再也不放过你了
You're goddamn right.You do some time, never let you go.
他们对待我就像是罪犯
They treat me like a criminal.
- 那么我迟早也会变成个罪犯   - 你就是个罪犯
- I'll end up a criminal. - You are a criminal.
干嘛说的那么直接？
Why'd you got to go and do that?
- 我只是想阐述观点  - 那你怎么不好好说？
- I'm trying to make a point. - Why don't you make your point?
你都烦死我了
You're making me tired all over.
算球
Fuck it then.
- 我听说你已经死了   - 是吗？
- I heard you were dead. - Yeah?
- 你没有听错   - 我听说的是你已经收手不干了
- You heard right.  - Word I got is you hung up your spurs.
- 这是怎么回事？  - 究竟怎么说的？
- What's that all about? - What's this?
谣言说基顿走正道了。我听说他在榨伊迪・芬纳兰
Rumor has it Keaton's gone straight.I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
那是谁？
Who's that?
她是来自富人区的一个重量级犯罪律师
She's a heavyweight criminal lawyer from uptown.
我听说她成了基顿的饭票
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
是吗，基顿？
How 'bout it, Keaton?
你有个律师老婆？
You a lawyer's wife?
你给她的是什么律师聘用金？？
What kind of retainer you giving her?
帮你朋友个忙，叫他收声
Do your friend a favor tell him to keep quiet.
迪恩・基顿…
Dean Keaton...
洗白了？
Gone clean?
我说不可能
Say it ain't so.
- 要不那卡车就是你抢的？   - 麦克，放过他吧
- Or was it you that hit that truck? - Mac, forget him.
你和你律师谈过没有？
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
整桩事情不过是勒索
This whole thing was a shakedown.
- 为什么这么说？   - 你被指认过几次？
- What makes you say that? - How many times you been in a lineup?
通常总是你和四个相仿的人
It's always you and four dummies.
警方总找些流浪汉来， 每次给他们十块
The PD are paying homeless guys $10 a head half the time.
他们不可能把五个罪犯放在一排
There's no way they'd line five felons in the same row.
- 那声音指认呢？ - 公设辩护律师都能搞定那个保你没事
- What's a voice lineup? - Public defender could get you out of that.
- 那我为什么被彻底搜身了？  - 是联邦人员
- Why the hell was I strip searched? - It was the feds.
有辆运枪车被截下了
A truck load of guns gets snagged.
海关的人到纽约警局要答案 于是他们来找我们
Customs comes down on NYPD for answers. They come up with us.
- 他们在抓救命稻草   - 有个家伙用手指弄我屁股。
- They're clutching at straws. - I had a guy's finger up my ass.
现在就是星期五了吗？
Is it Friday already?
是的，花花公子
Yeah, lover boy.
你想来一发吗？ 来吧，我会好好疼你的
You want a piece? Jump in. I'll love you.
那么究竟是哪个人渣抢了咱那他妈的货车？
So who in the goddamn piss hell stole our fucking truck?
- 你说什么？  - 是谁偷了那他妈的货车？
- What did you say? - Who stole the fucking truck?
- 我不想知道   - 谁问你了，正经人
- I don't want to know. - Who asked you, workingman?
做这事的人去死吧 我想知道的是，那跛子是什么人？
Fuck who did it.What I want to know is, who's the gimp?
- 他没什么   - 是你说的，我怎么知道？
- He's okay. - Says you. How do I know that?
怎么样，拐脚佬？你怎么回事？
What about it, pretzel man?What's your story?
他叫话痨
His name is Verbal.
话痨・肯特
Verbal Kint.
- 话痨？  - 对
- Verbal? - Yeah.
罗杰，真名。大家说我话太多
Roger, really. People say I talk too much.
我正想叫你闭嘴
I was going to tell you to shut up.
- 我们以前见过一两次   - 是在州局.我因为诈骗被抓进去。
- We met before, once or twice. - In County. I was in for fraud.
你那时也在指认队伍里。后来怎么样？
You were in a lineup then, too.What happened?
我出来了。90天，缓刑
I walked. 90 days, suspended.
- 那就是你干的喽   - 好了，大家听我说…
- So you did it. - All right, now look...
…我们都因这事被搅进来，对吧？
...we've all been put out by this whole thing, right?
我想我们该设法挽回点面子
I figure we owe it to ourselves to salvage a little dignity.
现在，我和芬斯特听说有一趟活儿
Now, me and Fenster heard about a little job.
你就不能冷静一下吗？
Why don't you just calm down?
听他说说又怎么了？
What do you care what he has to say?
我不过随便说说
I'm just talking here.
看来霍克内先生 似乎想听我要说什么…
It seems to me like Mr.Hockney wants to hear it...
…而我知道芬斯特亦有兴趣
...and I know Fenster's down.
你呢？伙计
What about you, guy?
我有兴趣
I'm interested.
看到没？
There. See?
我只想行使我的自由集会权
I'd like to exercise my right to free assembly.
闭会儿嘴不行吗？
Why don't you just shut up?
你是不明白
You're missing the point.
不
No.
不明白的人是你
You're missing the point.
我不想听你说任何事
I don't want to hear anything from you.
我对你的活儿没兴趣
I don't care about your job.
而且…
And...
…我不想和你们任何人有任何关联
...I want nothing to do with any of you.
我请你们原谅， 但你们全都可以见鬼去了
I beg your pardon,but you can all go to hell.
迪恩・基顿…
Dean Keaton...
…走正道了
...gone the high road.
这世界是怎么了？
What is the world coming to?
去他的
Fuck him.
事情就是这么开始的:
And that was how it started:
我们五个因为捏造的罪名
Five of us brought in on a trumped-up charge...
…被这些弱智关了进来
...to be leaned on by half-wits.
在这儿我真不能多说
I really can't talk about it much here.
警察们永远也想不到，而我现在知道的是…
What the cops never figured out,and what I know now...
…这些人永远不会被打垮，永不会被打倒
...was that these men would never break,never lie down.
永远不会屈服于任何人
Never bend over for anybody.
任何人都不行
Anybody.
加州  圣佩德罗(当日)
- 你是谁？  - 杰克・贝尔探员，FBI
- Who are you? - Agent Jack Baer, FBI.
- 死了多少人？ - 到现在发现15个
- How many dead? - 15 so far.
我们还在继续打捞水下的尸体
They're still pulling bodies out of the water.
- 有生还者吗？  - 两个
- Any survivors? - Two.
一个被送进了州立医院， 但他正在昏迷
One guy's in County hospital,but he's in a coma.
地方检察官带走了第二个家伙， 纽约来的跛子
The DA has a second guy,a cripple from New York.
局长要封锁这地方
The chief wants this place sealed off.
你有什么问题， 就给他打电话吧
If you have any questions, give him a call.
我是戴夫・奎恩，我在洛杉矶， 星期二才回来
This is Dave Kujan.I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
若有急事，可联系圣佩德罗警署的杰夫・拉宾…
If you need to reach me, contact Jeff Rabin of the San Pedro Police Department...
…拨内线112，祝你愉快
...at extension 112. Have a nice day.
（圣佩德罗警局）
- 我为什么不能见他？  - 我说了…
- Why can't I see him? - I told you...
…地方检察官昨晚来这里
...the DA came down here last night ready to arraign...
…准备在移交州局前就提审他。
...even before they moved him to County.
五分钟后，肯特的律师露面了…
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later...
…地方检察官出来时像是被妖怪扇晕了
...the DA comes out looking like
the bogeyman smacked him around.
他们接受了他的供述，与他达成协议
They take his statement,and they cut him a deal.
- 他们控他什么罪名没？  - 非法持械，二级轻罪
- Did they charge him with anything? - Weapons, misdemeanor 2.
什么意思？
What is that?
地方检察官能做到这样我给他点赞了，你懂吗？
I give the DA credit for getting that much,you understand?
请让一下，长官
Excuse me, sir.
整桩事情开始有政治色彩 市长昨晚来过
This whole thing has turned political.The mayor was here last night.
还有局长。今天早上州长也打了电话，知道吧？
The chief. This morning,the governor called, okay?
我告诉你，这家伙受到高层黑暗势力的保护，
I'm telling you, this guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of Darkness.
- 记住我说的话吧   - 他什么时候可保释外出？
- Take my word for it. - When does he post bail?
- 可能顶多再过两小时   - 我想要见见他
- Maybe two hours, tops. - I want to see him.
- 不行   - 我一定得见他
- No. - I gotta see him.
- 不，我做不到--   - 你必须得帮我
- No. I can't-- - You gotta do this for me.
我大老远来就是为了这事
I came a long way for this.
戴夫，拜托
Dave, please.
就算我让你见他， 他也不会跟你说的
Even if I let you talk to him,he won't talk to you.
他会怀疑被录音的
He's paranoid about being recorded.
- 他知道审讯室里有线路   - 我戒了
- He knows the rooms are wired. - I quit.
我不是审讯他，只不过是友好谈话罢了
This won't be an interrogation,just a friendly chat.
- 他不会进审讯室的  - 那就找别的地方
- He won't go into the interrogation room. - Then someplace else.
哪里呢？
Where?
不行，不行
No, no.
若这是毒品交易，那毒品呢？ 如果是袭击，那又是谁指使的？
If this was a dope deal, where's the dope?If it was a hit, who called it?
我相信这些问题在你心里已经有了一大堆疯狂的理论来回答
I'm sure you have a host of wild theories to answer all these questions.
- 你很清楚我的想法   - 真是疯了，而且也没什么意义
- You know what I think. - That's crazy, and it doesn't even matter.
这家伙已经得到完全豁免 他的背景也已经查出来了
The guy's got total immunity.His story checks out.
- 他不知道你想知道的东西   - 我没认为他知道，并不完全知道
- He doesn't know what you want to know. - I don't think he does, not exactly.
但他的事情远没有那么简单，相信我
But there's a lot more to his story,believe me.
我想知道为什么有27个人死在那个码头
I wanna know why 27 men died on that pier...
看来与价值九千一百万的毒品有关 但毒品却不在那儿
...for what looks to be $91 million worth of dope that wasn't there.
而最重要的是，我要确认迪恩・基顿的死讯
And above all,I want to be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
他确实死了
He's dead.
得了。就两小时。到他被保释就结束
Come on. Two hours.Just till he makes bail.
他们都死了
They're all dead.
我才不在乎你说的这个基顿有多厉害…
I don't care how tough you say Keaton was...
…那条船上没人能生还
...nobody on that boat could've come out alive.
- 他能说话吗？  - 他一小时前醒来
- Is he talking? - He regained consciousness an hour ago.
说了些话，不是英语 然后就停下了
He spoke, not English, then he lapsed.
- 是匈牙利话吗？  - 我不知道，也许是吧
- Hungarian? - That might have been it.
- 他们大部分是匈牙利人  - 你得把这穿上
- Most of them were Hungarians. - You gotta put this on.
烧伤病人很容易感染
Burn victims are very susceptible to infection.
还有，那儿是禁烟的
And, of course, there's no smoking.
请戴上口罩，还有别去碰他
Keep your mask up.Please don't touch him.
他会死吗？
Is he gonna die?
他全身有六成被烧伤 肋骨断裂--
He's burned 60 percent of his body,broken ribs--
叫医院保安来.叫个人守在门口
Call security. Put a man on the door.
- 他会有危险？  - 对
- Is he dangerous? - Yes.
去吧
Do it.
快去
Do it now.
约尔吗？我是贝尔 从洛杉矶给你打来的
Joel? Baer. Down at LA County.
他们在码头找到的那人 叫阿科西・卡瓦什
Look, the guy they pulled out of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
是的，我明白
Yes, I'm sure.
不，他受了重伤
No, he's all fucked up.
我听不清
I can't hear you.
闭会儿嘴好吗？我在打电话
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
对
Yes.
不，直至我派人来看着他
No, not till I put a man on him.
派个会说匈牙利语的人来
Send me someone who can speak Hungarian.
他醒着 他说话就像泰国妓女
He's awake.He's talking like a Thai hooker.
凯撒・苏斯
Keyser Soze.
- 什么？  - 凯撒・苏斯！
- What?- Keyser Soze!
这是怎么了？
No shit?
到法院去找丹・曼厮固
Call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice...
…还有海关的戴夫・奎恩
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
话痨，这是海关的奎恩探员
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
他想在你离开前问几个问题
He wants to ask you a few questions before you go.
- 什么问题？  - 大部分是关于迪恩・基顿的
- What about? - About a Dean Keaton, mostly.
但我想先由在纽约的指认谈起
I'd like to start at the lineup back in New York.
- 我能喝杯咖啡吗？  - 稍后再说吧，先说说指认时的事
- Can I get some coffee? - In a while. Let's talk about the lineup.
我真的很口渴 我就像孩子般的容易脱水
I'm really thirsty.I used to dehydrate as a kid.
有次我尿出的小便就像涕一样
Once I got so bad my piss come out like snot.
- 就是那种又浓又粘的--  - 我去给你弄他妈的咖啡
- It was all thick and gooey-- - I'll get your fucking coffee.
顺便给我也冲一杯
Get me one, too, while you're at it.
那家伙太紧张了
That guy is tense.
紧张足以致命
Tension is a killer.
我曾经加入过在伊利诺州邵崎市 的一个男声四重唱组合
I used to be in a barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois.
男中音就叫基普・迪斯金， 大胖子
The baritone was this guy named Kip Diskin, big fat guy.
胖的像逆戟鲸。他每天早上都紧张的要命--
Like, orca fat.He was so stressed in the morning--
- 你知道我们现在是想帮你  - 当然，我很感激
- You know we're trying to help you.- Sure, and I appreciate that.
我也想帮你，奎恩探员 我喜欢警察
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan.I like cops.
我曾想成为联邦人员， 可是我的--
I would've liked to have been a fed,but my CP--
你没跟我们完全交代 我知道你知道些事情
You're not tellin' us everything.I know you know something.
我已经全都对地方检察官说了
I told the DA everything I know.
我知道你喜欢基顿
I know you like Keaton.
- 我明白你认为他是好人  - 我知道他很好
- I know you think he's a good man. - I know he was good.
他曾是个贪污的警察
He was a corrupt cop.
对，15年前的事了，他还是个好贼
Sure. 15 years ago,but he was a good thief.
反正条子们不让他做合法生意。
The cops wouldn't let him go legit.
迪恩・基顿是一坨屎
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
你想从我身上得到点什么？
Are you trying to get a rise out of me?
- 我只想听听你的故事  - 全在那儿了
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
能抽支烟吗？
May I have a cigarette?
- 根据你的供述--  - 给个火
- According to your statement-- - I need a light.
根据你的供述， 你只是个小毛贼…
According to your statement,you're a short-con operator...
…不入流的--
...run-of-the-mill--
根据你的供述， 你只是个小毛贼…
According to your statement,you're a short-con operator...
…不入流的骗子
...run-of-the-mill scams.
这些应该已经被禁止了，里面的东西是不被承认的
It's been suppressed.Anything in there is inadmissible.
我知道，你做了桩好交易，完全豁免
I know. Sweet deal you have here.Total immunity.
我可是被诉持械 还有六个月的日子得熬
I do have the weapons charge.I'm lookin' at six whole months hard time.
认识一个叫鲁比・迪莫的商人吗？
You know a dealer named Ruby Deemer?
认识一个叫约翰・保罗的教徒吗？
You know a religious guy named John Paul?
- 知道阿提卡（著名监狱）的鲁比吗？  - 我和他没什么瓜葛
- You know Ruby's in Attica? - He didn't have my lawyer.
我认识鲁比，他很受人尊敬
I know Ruby. He's big on respect.
他是我的好朋友，很喜欢我
He's a good friend of mine,likes me very much.
我知你的证供已被封存 可鲁比的关系很广
I know your testimony is sealed.Ruby's well connected.
他有许多内部的朋友愿为他效力
He's got lots of friends inside who do favors for him.
如果他知道你把他的名字供给了地方检察官，他会怎么说呢？
What would he say if he found out you dropped his name to the DA?
- 上面根本没提鲁比的事   - 可我会这么对他说
- There's nothing there on Ruby. - I'll be sure to mention that to him.
知道我从这行学了什么？ 就是如何认出凶手
Know what I've learned on the job?How to spot a murderer.
就说你抓了一宗谋杀案的三个疑犯
Say you arrest three guys for the same killing.
你把他们关通宵
Put them in jail overnight.
到了第二天早上， 谁要是睡着了，谁就是凶手
Next morning,whoever's sleeping is your man.
如果你犯了罪，等到被捕 你的戒心就松懈了
If you're guilty, you know you're caught.You let your guard down.
-  你听得懂吗？  - 不
- You follow me? - No.
让我直说重点吧
Let me get to the point.
我比你聪明， 我会查出我要知道的事
I'm smarter than you,and I'm gonna find out what I wanna know.
我会查出来的，无论你喜不喜欢
I'll get it, whether you like it or not.
我不是告密的人
I'm not a rat.
谢谢
Thanks.
我在危地马拉摘咖啡豆的时候曾经做过新鲜咖啡
When I was pickin' beans in Guatemala we used to make fresh coffee.
我的意思是直接从树上摘下的，好喝极了
Right off the trees, I mean. That was good.
- 这简直是屎，不过我是在警局里   - 我们能继续吗？
- This is shit, but I'm in a police station. - Can we get started again?
指认结束后怎样了？
What happened after the lineup?
那值班的中士对我说不能释放你
The desk sergeant was telling me he couldn't release you.
你能相信吗？你甚至未被起诉
Can you believe that?You weren't even charged.
该死的警察
Damn police.
我要给你的脸拍照
I wanna have pictures taken of your face.
- 明天就送到地方检察官那儿   - 算了吧
- I'll take them to the DA tomorrow. - Forget about it.
当然不行。星期一我就会把这事报到大陪审团去
I'll have this thing in front of a grand jury by Monday.
我不想再谈这事了，好吗？
I don't want to talk about it, okay?
弗提和雷诺怎么说？
What did Fortier and Renault say?
他们需要多些时间考虑投资
They asked for more time to think about investing.
该死的
Damn it.
需要多些时间干什么？
More time for what?
无论你怎么掩盖我的历史 他们还是会查到我的
No matter how you cover my tracks they're still gonna find out about me.
给我点信心
Give me some credit.
我会帮你撇开这事的，我们去找大陪审团
I got you this far.Let's go to the grand jury.
- 如果不这样，这事不会停--   - 这永远不会停，句号。
- This isn't gonna stop if we don't-- - It's never going to stop, period.
下星期所有投资者都将离弃我们
By next week, every investor in the city is gonna be walking away from us.
这事完了
It's finished.
我完了
I'm finished.
别轻言放弃，基顿
Don't give up on me now.
这永远也不会停
It's never gonna stop.
我爱你
I love you.
他们今晚毁了我
They ruined me in there tonight.
我爱你
I love you.
你听到了吗？
Do you hear me?
（寻狗启事）
什么？
What?
好了
All right.
去我家吧
Let's just go to my place.
我们明天再操心这些。
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
走吧
Let's go.
芬斯特和麦克马纳斯有个精明的提议:
Fenster and McManus had a cagey proposition:
快速行动，高风险，利润也大
A fast-jump, high-risk, long money.
我们都知道那行得通
We all knew it could be done.
我琢磨这事办坏了就意味着杀人
The way I figured,to do it wrong meant killing.
要办好就得五个人
To do it right took five men.
五个人意味着基顿加入
Five men meant Keaton.
基顿令人信服
Keaton took convincing.
纽约警察出租公司
New York's finest taxi service.
胡说
Bullshit.
他们早就不运作了
They don't operate anymore.
麦克马纳斯有个朋友在十四区 他们星期四要出来干一票
McManus has a friend in the 14th precinct.They're coming out for one job, Thursday.
他们接了一个从南非走私绿宝石的家伙
They're pickin' up a guy smuggling emeralds from South America.
麦克马纳斯已经找到了销赃人
McManus already has a fence set up.
- 销赃人？是谁？   - 是个加州人，叫瑞德福特
- A fence? Who? - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
- 我从未听说过他  - 你一定要来
- I never heard of him. - You have to come.
- 我来与不来，与你何干？  - 他们不认识我，你认识我
- What's it to you whether I do it or not? - They don't know me. You do.
除非你去，否则他们不要我
They won't take me unless you go.
看看我，我需要这笔钱
Look at me. I need this.
你是说你不需要吗？这是你家吗？
You're telling me you don't need this?Is this your place?
我不是在打击你 你把这律师骗得不错
I'm not knocking you. You got a good scam going with this lawyer.
对不起
Sorry.
没事
It's okay.
你说你们是来真的？那不错
You say it's the real thing? That's cool.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我不是道上的
I was out of line.
可他们仍不放过我们 你明白这点
But they're never gonna stop with us.You know that.
即使像你这样清白，他们仍不放过你
As clean as you get,they'll never let you go now.
这么干，既能给条子们颜色看，同时我们也得了好处
This way, we hit the cops where it hurts,and we get well in the meantime.
你真的没事吗？
You sure you're okay?
会没事的
I'll be all right.
你看…
Look, I...
- …我有时候会--   - 别说了
- ...sometimes get-- - Forget it.
我今晚可能会泻血
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
那么…
So...
…他们想怎么下手？
...how do they wanna do it?
麦克马纳斯想开枪 我反对
McManus wants to go in shooting.I say no.
芬斯特呢？霍克内呢？
Fenster? Hockney?
他们都很生气，什么都干的出来
They're pretty pissed off.They'll do anything.
我有个办法不用杀任何人
I got a way to do it without killing anyone.
可就像我说的， 没有你，他们不会让我加入
But like I say,they won't let me in without you.
三百万？
$3 million?
也许更多
Maybe more.
不杀人
No killing.
只要照我的方法做就不会
Not if we do it my way.
（警车）
纽约警察出租车公司不是你通常认为的出租车
New York's finest taxi service was not your normal taxi service.
那是纽约贪污警察的高利润生财工具…
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the NYPD that ran a high-profit racket...
…他们全城接送走私客和毒贩
...driving smugglers and drug dealers all over the city.
付上每公里三百元的价钱， 你就有了私人的蓝白...
For $300 a mile,you got your own blue and white...
警察护卫，他们甚至还有名片
...and a police escort.They even had their own business cards.
没过多久，有人开始问话，这项计程车服务关张了
After a while, somebody started asking questions, and the taxi service shut down.
从那以后内务部一直在等着抓他们现行
Ever since then, Internal Affairs has been waiting to catch them in the act.
我们就从这里下手
That's where we came in.
- 旅程如何？   - 真他妈好
- So, how was the flight? - Fuckin' great.
这些够送我去斯丹顿岛吗？
Will this get me to Staten Island?
开什么玩笑？ 就是把你送到科特角去也行
Are you kiddin' me?This will get you to Cape Cod.
麦克马纳斯去接生意， 芬斯特安排车辆
McManus came to us with the job.Fenster got the vans.
霍克内提供硬家伙
Hockney supplied the hardware.
我则想办法令各人不致被杀
I came through with how to do it so no one got killed.
基顿？ 基顿把整桩事添上最后一笔
But Keaton?Keaton put on the finishing touch.
帮我们五个人小整纽约警局一把
A little "fuck you" from the five of us to the NYPD.
看着点
Watch this.
小心
Careful.
搞什么，混球
Come on, asshole!
狗屎！
Holy shit!
- 别动，混蛋！  - 立刻扔掉，杂种！
- Don't move, you fucker! - Drop it now, motherfucker!
把他妈的枪丢掉！快丢掉！
Drop the fuckin' gun! Drop it!
别他妈的碰他妈任何东西
Don't fuckin' touch a fuckin' thing.
- 你们想要干什么？  - 把那该死的东西拿开
- What do you guys want? - Put your fuckin' thing away.
我们是警察，蠢货！
We're cops! Stupid assholes!
- 小心玻璃！  - 他妈的别动，杂种！
- Watch the glass! - Don't fuckin' move, motherfucker!
- 想来个子弹浴吗？胖子  - 闭嘴！
- You want a buckshot shampoo, chubby? - Shut up!
他妈的
Fuck.
下午好，小肉排。把东西给我
'Afternoon, my little pork chops.Give me the shit.
- 别动！  - 把那东西给他！
- Don't move! - Give him the shit!
快把那该死的东西给他！
Give him the fuckin' thing!
Give him the fuckin' shit, man!
快点！拿来！
Hurry up! Come on!
- 还有钱  - 没有钱了
- Now the money! - There's no money.
- 把钱交出来！  - 没有他妈的钱
- Give me the money now! - There's no fuckin' money.
把钱给他！
Give him the fuckin' money!
- 快！把钱给他！  - 把钱给我！
- Do it! Give him the money! - Give me the money!
- 把钱给他！  - 快点！
- Give him the money! - Hurry up!
你们知道我他妈是谁吗？
You know who the fuck I am?
你们这些人知道我他妈是谁吗？ 妈的！
You people know who the fuck I am? Fuck!
现在知道了，傻逼
We do now, jerk-off.
混蛋
Cocksucker.
等等，那算什么？
Wait a minute. What's that?
这到底算什么？
What the fuck?
天啊！
Holy shit!
走！
Go!
基顿打了个匿名电话
Keaton made an anonymous phone call.
新闻界在警察之前抵达现场
The press was on the scene before the police were.
三天后，史道及瑞兹被控罪
Strausz and Rizzi were indicted three days later.
几周内，又有50多个警察跟他们一起完蛋
Within a few weeks,50 more cops went down with them.
人人都被搞得蛋疼，从局长往下
Everybody got it right in the ass,from the chief on down.
干得漂亮
It was beautiful.
我欠你两块半
I owe you $2.50.
基顿博士
Dr.Keaton.
- 比我想的要多   - 销赃人什么时候到？
- There's more here than I thought. - When's the fence coming?
瑞德福特不会主动来见我，总是我去找他
Redfoot never comes to see me.I always go to see him.
在加州？
In California?
是的，话痨，在加州，芬斯特和我--
Yes, Verbal, in California. Fenster and I--
等等，先收声 你和芬斯特？不行
Wait, hold the fuckin' phone.You and Fenster? No.
- 你们他妈的想耍我？   - 那么派谁去？
- You fuckin' kiddin' me? - So then, who's gonna go?
我们一起去
We all go.
你他妈有什么问题？伙计
What's your fuckin' problem, man?
我的问题就是， 你和芬斯特在加州度蜜月
My problem, is you and Fenster honeymooning in California...
…而我们其他人只能坐在这儿撸管
...while the rest of us are sittin' here holding our dicks.
这活儿已经结束了
The job's over.
等事情冷下来
Cool it.
洛杉矶是个低调藏身的好地方
LA's a good place to lay low for a while.
想要跳舞吗？
You wanna dance?
女士们
Ladies.
我提议大家干一杯
I would like to propose a toast.
敬你的
There you go.
敬话痨先生…
To Mr.Verbal...
…智多星
...the man with the plan.
我们会错过班机的
We're gonna miss the flight.
别这样等， 随便给她留张便条
Don't do this.Send her a note. Something.
我说了来得及的
I said we'll make it.
我们快要误机了
We're gonna miss the plane.
她会理解的
She'll understand.
感人啊，真的
That's heartwarming. Really.
我眼泪盈眶
I'm weepy.
到外面去等好吗？
You wanna wait outside?
你们想知道发生的事 我正和你们说实话
You guys wanted to know what happened.I'm telling you.
继续吧，话痨
Come on, Verbal.
你以为是在跟谁说话呢？ 你要我相信他真的洗手了？
Who do you think you're talkin' to?You expect me to believe that he retired?
就为了个女人？
For a woman?
胡扯,基顿是在利用她
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- 他爱他   - 当然
- He loved her. - Sure.
我要相信袭击出租车不是他的主意
I'm supposed to believe that hitting the taxi service wasn't his idea.
- 都是芬斯特和麦克马纳斯   - 基顿当过四年的警察
- It was all Fenster and McManus. - Keaton was a cop for four years.
谁会比他知道的更清楚？
Who else would know better?
- 这趟活儿全是他的印记  - 但伊迪使他全改变了
- That job had his name on it. - Edie had him turned around.
让我这么跟你说吧
Let me tell you something.
我了解迪恩・基顿
I know Dean Keaton.
过去三年来我一直在调查他
I've been investigating him for the past three years.
我知道这家伙是个冷血的杂种
The guy I know was a cold-blooded bastard.
警队开除他前 IAD三次控他谋杀
IAD indicted him on three counts of murder before he was kicked off the force.
别告诉我妓女也有颗金子般的心
Don't sell me the hooker with a heart of gold.
你完全弄错了
You got him all wrong.
我有吗？
Do I?
迪恩・基顿在警队时有七次被控罪的记录
Dean Keaton was under indictment seven times while he was on the force.
每一次不是证人翻供
In every case,witnesses either reversed their testimony...
…就是在出庭前就死亡
...or died before they could testify.
等到他们终于以诈骗罪给他定罪，他在辛辛监狱待了五年
When they finally did nail him for fraud,he spent five years in Sing Sing.
他在里面杀了三个囚犯
He killed three prisoners inside.
当然，我不能证明此事
Of course, I can't prove this...
…但我也不能证明他没有做
...but I can't prove the best part either.
迪恩・基顿死过一次
Dean Keaton was dead.
你知道那故事吗？
Did you know that?
两年前他死于火灾，有一个要指证他的证人…
He died in a fire two years ago,during an investigation into the murder...
…被杀，调查此案时
...of a witness who was going to testify against him.
两个人看见迪恩・基顿走进他的一间货仓，然后货仓爆炸了
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into a warehouse he owned just before it blew up.
他们说他去检查漏气的煤气管道
They said he went in to check a leaking gas main.
结果它爆炸了，迪恩・基顿在里面
It blew up and took all of Dean Keaton with it.
爆炸发生三个月内， 那两个目击者死了
Within three months of the explosion,the two witnesses, they were dead.
一个是在车内自杀
One killed himself in his car.
另一个从打开的电梯井跌下
The other fell down an open elevator shaft.
咱们开场吧
Let's get this show on the road.
我们说的可不是这样。 现在有太多--
This is not what we discussed.There are too many--
我答应他死之前我们会离开
I promise we'll be out before he blows his porch light.
- 我中午还有个会   - 五分钟
- I have a noon meeting. - Five minutes.
大家冷静点，好吗
Everyone calm down, all right?
我要你问他码头枪战的事
I want you to ask this man about the shootout in the harbor.
- 他说他们在买--  - 是毒品，我们知道
- He says they were buying-- - Dope. We know.
他不知道他们要买什么， 但肯定不是毒品
He doesn't know what they were buying, but not dope.
- 是人 - 什么？
- People. - What?
他需要保证…
He needs guarantees...
- 他在说什么？保证？  - 他说他有生命危险
- What is he talking about, guarantees? - He says his life is in danger.
他看到那魔鬼在望着他
He saw the Devil Looked him in the eye.
- 我走了   - 不，等等
- I'm on my way. - No, wait a minute.
要他告诉他那个他跟我说过的…
Ask him to tell him what he told me...
…那个魔鬼的事
...about the Devil.
魔鬼是谁？
Who's the Devil?
凯撒・苏斯
Keyser Soze.
凯撒・苏斯？
Keyser Soze?
他在码头上，大开杀戒
He was in the harbor, killing many men.
他看见了凯撒・苏斯？
He saw Keyser Soze?
- 他看到了他的脸   - 好，好
- He saw his face. - All right.
让他告诉她 那人的长相是怎样的
Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
形容出来
Describe him.
六星期前，我接到一个匿名电话…
Six weeks ago,I get an anonymous phone call...
…说能在马蒂诺餐厅找到基顿 他也确实在
...telling me I can find Keaton eating at Mondino's, and there he is.
由于他从未从诈死中获益
Because he never profited from his alleged death...
…也因为那件本来怀疑他的谋杀案我们已定罪另一个人
...and we convicted someone else of the murder we tried to pin on him...
…我们只得放过他
...we had to let him go.
他死了够长的时间 那件谋杀案风头已过
He was dead just long enough for the murder rap to blow over.
然后他就吃午餐了
And then he had lunch.
我对那一无所知
I don't know about that.
我不认为你知道什么， 可你说看见基顿死了
I don't think you do,but you say you saw Keaton die.
我想你是在掩护他， 而他仍藏身在某处
I think you're covering his ass,and he's still out there.
我认为他就是码头混战的幕后主使
I think he's behind that circus at the harbor.
我打赌他在利用你，因为你蠢 而且以为他是你朋友
My bet is he's using you because you're stupid and think he's your friend.
你跟我说他死了，就这样
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
我想在回纽约前确定他已死
I wanna be sure before I go back to New York.
他什么幕后都不是， 是那个律师
He wasn't behind anything.It was the lawyer.
什么律师？
What lawyer?
在我还在男声四重唱组时--
Back when I was in that barbershop quartet--
你以为我不知道你对地方检察官有隐瞒？
You don't think I know you held out on the DA?
你到底隐瞒了什么？
What did you leave out?
我能在十分钟内打电话找到鲁比
I could be on the phone to Ruby in 10 minutes.
-  地方检察官已经豁免我了  - 我还没有
- The DA gave me immunity. - Not from me.
你没从我这儿得到豁免，你这坨屎
You get no immunity from me,you piece of shit.
每一个我关进监狱的罪犯， 每一个欠我人情的条子…
Every criminal I have put in prison,every cop that owes me a favor...
…每一个街头混混和人渣…
...every creep and scumbag that walks the street...
…都会知道话痨・肯特的大名。你老实跟我交代…
...will know the name of Verbal Kint.You talk to me...
…不然他们给你的宝贝豁免权…
...or that precious immunity they grant you...
…不会比一张悬赏要你命的打印纸更有价值
...won't be worth the paper the contract put out on your life is printed on.
还有个律师
There was a lawyer.
小林
Kobayashi.
- 他杀了基顿吗？   - 不是，但我肯定基顿已经死了
- Is he the one that killed Keaton? - No, but I'm sure Keaton is dead.
说服我
Convince me.
告诉我每一个细节
Tell me every last detail.
我们抵达洛杉矶去见麦克马纳斯的销赃人，瑞德福特
We arrived in Los Angeles and met McManus' fence, Redfoot.
他有着不错的名声，看来似乎是个好人
He had a good reputation.Seemed like a good guy.
- 可我们还得多了解   - 还好吗？
- Still, we should have known better. - How you doing?
- 还好.你呢？   - 不坏，没啥可抱怨的
- Good. You? - Not bad. Can't complain.
你怎么样，芬斯特？
How's it going, Fenster?
不需要打开吧？
Don't need to open it, right?
你一定是基顿
You must be Keaton.
瑞德福特，迪恩・基顿
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
- 托德・霍克内，还有话痨・肯特.  - 话痨，智多星？
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint. - Verbal, the man with the plan.
有兴趣再干一把吗？
You interested in more work?
- 我们一直在找活干  - 我们在休假
- We're always looking for extra work. - We're on vacation.
那太糟了
That's too bad.
我有大堆的活儿， 可惜没有好手
I got a ton of work and no good people.
- 没有你们这样的人   - 是什么活儿？
- Not like you guys. - What's the job?
有个德克萨斯的珠宝商 叫索尔
There's this jeweler out of Texas named Saul.
他在市区某个酒店租了间套房
He rents a suite in some downtown hotel.
他免费为人估价 有时会买，有时不买
He does free appraisals.Sometimes he buys, sometimes he doesn't.
传言他带有大笔现金
The word is,he carries around a lot of cash.
所以我想， 我收货，你拿绿票子
So I figure, I keep the merchandise,you keep the green.
- 简单  - 安保呢？
- Simple. - What about security?
两个保镖，你们完全可以搞定
A couple of bodyguards.Nothing you couldn't handle.
给我点时间考虑下？
Give me time to check it out?
我从来不会对你失望，兄弟
I expect nothing less from you, man.
很高兴见到你，我们会给你打电话
Good to see you. We'll call you.
好好的在洛杉矶享受
Enjoy LA. Get yourself laid.
有个纽约的朋友告诉我 你认识斯波克・荷利
A friend in New York tells me that you knew Spook Hollis.
我听说，你和斯波克一同坐牢
The way I hear it,you did time with ol' Spook.
是个好人，对吧？
A good man, wasn't he?
我以前曾为他贩过毒
I used to run dope for him.
可惜他挂了
Too bad he got shivved.
我干的
I shivved him.
我现在告诉你 总比以后别人传给你好
Better you hear it from me now than from somebody else later.
我很感激
I appreciate that.
只是出于好奇…
But just out of curiosity...
是为了生意，还是私怨？
...was it business or personal?
两者都有点
A bit of both.
就如我说的…
Like I said...
…若你有兴趣，可给我电话
...you give me a call if you're interested.
有问题吗？
Is there a problem?
只干一次
One job.
这是说好的
That was the deal.
只干一次？
One job?
太好了
That's a good one.
基顿全力抵制， 但人不能改变身份
Keaton fought it as best he could,but a man can't change what he is.
他可以跟别人说他变了， 但绝不能说服自己
He can convince anyone he's someone else,but never himself.
麦克马纳斯唠叨了一天， 于是我们又干回本行
It took one day with McManus nagging,and we went back to work.
我下了车，那事全被搅了
I get out of my car,and the thing is wrecked.
我向另外那辆车的后座看去 那女人完全脱光了
I look in the backseat of the other car,and this woman's totally naked.
- 我笑到快透不过气来  - 上车吧，索尔
- I'm laughin' so hard I can't breathe. - Get in the car, Saul.
- 别动，混蛋！  - 待在那！
- Freeze, motherfucker! - Stay right there!
那边还有一个人
There's a second one here, somewhere.
给我公文箱，给我他妈的公文箱！
Gimme the case. Give me the fuckin' case!
给我他妈的公文箱，我最后一次跟你说…
Give me the fuckin' case.I'm tellin' you for the last time.
给我他妈的公文箱！
Give me the fuckin' case!
- 过来！  - 别动！
- Come on! - Don't move!
把箱子递出来
Hand over the case.
把他妈的箱子递出来
Hand over the fuckin' case.
过来，咱们走！
Come on, let's go!
- 快！  - 今天真倒霉，他妈的
- Come on! - Bad day. Fuck it.
快走了！
Let's go!
操
Fuck.
- 对我来说就是堆废品  - 狗屎
- Looks like a lot of china to me. - Shit.
伙计们，准备
Guys, come on.
- 你想干什么？  - 我要杀了他
- What are you doin'? - I'm gonna kill him.
我们照你的方式做了，现在按我的来办
We did it your way, now we'll do it mine.
- 你要杀他吗？  - 我去和他谈
- You gonna kill him? - I'll deal with him.
- 你最好能谈拢，否则我就  - 闭嘴
- You'd better, or I'm gonna. - Shut up.
我拿这东西能干什么？
What am I supposed to do with that?
喂那跛子吧，能帮他止痛。我也不知道那是什么
Feed it to the gimp. Ease his pain.I don't know what that is.
- 什么意思？  - 我不知情
- What do you mean? - I don't know.
是个律师给我这趟活儿
I got thrown this job by some lawyer.
谁？
Who?
我不知道，是个英国佬
I don't know. Some limey.
他是个中间人 他没说，我没问。
He's a middleman for somebody.He doesn't say, I don't ask.
- 你真他妈是坨屎！  - 草泥马！
- You're fuckin' full of shit!- Fuck you.
- 草泥马！  - 听我说
- Fuck you. - Listen to me.
我们想要见他，行吗
We wanna meet him, okay?
有意思
That's funny.
昨晚他给我打电话，说想要见你们
He called me last night.He says he wants to meet you guys.
好，我们去见他
Okay, we'll meet him.
- 我会给你电话  - 好，我们走
- I'll call you. - Good. Let's go.
我不喜欢这样，等等。还有件事，好小子:
I don't like it. Wait a minute.One more thing, tough guy:
再玩什么花样，我就杀了你
Any more surprises, and I'm gonna kill you.
你还真是条好汉。不过帮我个忙，好吗？
You're such a tough guy.But do me a favor, all right?
快他妈在我面前消失
Get the fuck off my dick.
不！
No!
拴好那宠物狗
Put a leash on that puppy.
索尔被杀真是糟糕透顶
It's an awful shame about Saul gettin' whacked.
警察要追查是谁干的
Cops'll be lookin' for the guys who did it.
迟早，他们会来找我打听
Sooner or later,they're gonna come around askin' me.
祝你们晚安，女士们
You have a sweet night, ladies.
草泥马
Fuck you.
- 那么这个律师--   - 小林
- So this lawyer-- - Kobayashi.
- 是瑞德福特引来的？  - 对
- Came from Redfoot. - Right.
和地方检察官说的时候为何漏了这段？
And why leave this out when you talked to the DA?
戴夫，有人找你
Dave, someone to see you.
我满世界找你
I've been looking all over for you.
你还在找昨晚大屠杀失踪的可卡因？
You still after that coke that took a walk out of that bloodbath yesterday?
不用查了，没有可卡因
You can stop looking. There was no coke.
我在州立医院找到了一个从排水管道救上的人…
I've been in LA County talking to a guy they pulled out of a drainpipe...
…昨晚枪战后的幸存者
...yesterday after the shootout.
今早他苏醒了，开始说话
He came to this morning,he started talking.
他是匈牙利匪帮的一员 他们和阿根廷黑帮交易
He's part of a Hungarian mob.They dealt with gwats from Argentina.
他说根本与毒品交易无关
He says it was definitely not a dope deal.
- 但是有--  - 我知道.可他说没有毒品
- But there were-- - We know. But he says no on the dope.
这匈牙利人告诉我，他们第二天要去土耳其
This Hungarian tells me they were pulling stumps for Turkey the next day.
他们没时间做那种货 也无意运毒
They had no time for that kind of product,and no means to move it.
- 那钱是做什么的？  - 他不知道
- What's the money for? - He didn't know.
除了几个关键人物，做事的没人知道
No one doing the deal knew except for a few key people.
他说那些人都闭口不提
They were all very hush about it, he says.
- 无论那是什么，都牵连重大   - 我不太明白
- Whatever it was, it was very sensitive. - I don't get it.
那个跛脚的纽约人在你这吗？
You got the cripple in there from New York?
他提过凯撒・苏斯没？
Did he mention Keyser Soze?
谁？
Who?
耐心听我说
Just bear with me here.
-谁是凯撒・苏斯？ -操！
- Who's Keyser Soze? - Fuck!
我们讨论这个都一个半小时了
We've been goin' over this for an hour and a half.
我们只需要找到瑞德福特 然后离开这鬼地方
What we need to do is find Redfoot and get the hell out of here now.
我们要做的是思考
What we need to do is think.
回想一下
Think back.
一个实力人物…
Somebody with power...
…一个有能力从纽约到洛杉矶追踪我们的人
...somebody capable of tracking us from New York to LA.
- 我们在这儿干什么鬼事？  - 我们在等
- What the hell are we doing here? - We're waiting.
- 坐下   - 不，我火着呢，他妈的烦透了
- Sit down. - No. I'm hot, and I'm fuckin' bored.
霍克内先生，停下
Mr.Hockney, do stay.
基顿先生
Mr.Keaton.
芬斯特先生，我从档案照片认出他…
Mr.Fenster I recognize from his mug shots...
…麦克马纳斯先生也是
...as well as Mr.McManus.
我只能猜你就是肯特先生，干掉索尔・伯格的人
I can only assume that you are Mr.Kint,the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
我的雇主致上他的感谢，一份意想不到的好处
My employer sends his gratitude,a most unexpected benefit.
我就是小林先生
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
我的雇主要我带份建议给你们几位先生
I have been asked by my employer to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
- 你想怎样？  - 我雇主想你们为他效劳
- What do you want? - My employer requires your services.
一趟活儿，工作一天，非常危险
One job, one day's work. Very dangerous.
他没预计你们全部能活命，但活下来的…
He does not expect all of you to live.But those of you who do...
…可以分得九千一百万，怎么合适怎么分
...will have $91 million to divide between you in any way you see fit.
谁是你的老板？
Who's your boss?
我为凯撒・苏斯做事
I work for Keyser Soze.
谁是凯撒・苏斯？
Who's Keyser Soze?
我有个忽然冒出来的灵感
Judging by the sudden change in mood...
…感觉你的合伙人可以告诉你
...I feel sure the rest of your associates can tell you.
我带来一个苏斯先生直接提出的建议
I come with an offer directly from Mr.Soze.
- 是个命令，实际上  - 你什么意思，“命令”？
- An order, actually. - What do you mean, "an order"?
1981年，你在纽约巴弗洛区参与骑劫一辆货车
In 1981, you participated in the hijacking of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
货物是原钢材料，原属于苏斯先生…
The cargo was raw steel,steel which belonged to Mr.Soze...
…本应送到巴基斯坦作核反应堆
...and which was destined for Pakistan to be used in a nuclear reactor.
那是违反联合国条例的大生意
A most profitable violation of UN Regulations.
你没办法知道这个，基顿先生...
You had no way of knowing this...
因为船运这批钢材的人为苏斯先生效劳
...because the fellow shipping the steel was working for Soze...
也毫不知情
...without his knowledge.
今年初，芬斯特先生与麦克马纳斯先生…
Earlier this year,Mr.Fenster and Mr.McManus...
在纽瓦克机场骑劫了一架双螺旋桨货机
...hijacked a two-prop cargo flight out of Newark airport.
机上载有黄金和铂金丝，也是给巴基斯坦的
The plane was carrying gold and platinum wiring also set for Pakistan.
两个月前，霍克内先生偷了辆货车…
Two months ago,Mr.Hockney stole a truck...
…装着枪械零件，途经皇后区
...carrying gun parts through Queens.
枪零件本要由纽约州政府销毁
Gun parts which were set to be destroyed by the state of New York.
它们在一个中途站丢失了，并被转送贝尔法斯特
They were to be lost in a way station and rerouted to Belfast.
又一次，苏斯先生利用了不知情的卒子
Again, Mr.Soze using pawns who had no knowledge.
这样我们就找到了肯特先生
Which brings us to Mr.Kint.
九个月前，苏斯先生的…
Nine months ago, one of Mr.Soze's...
…一个不聪明的手下陷入一场复杂的诈骗
...less than intelligent couriers was taken in a complicated confidence scam...
…是一个跛子
...by a cripple.
他被骗去六万二千元
He was relieved of $62,000.
花些时间才找齐你们
Now, it has taken us some time to find you.
我们本来意图在纽约你们被捕后找你们的
Our intention was to approach you after your apprehension in New York.
是你安排的指认
You set up the lineup.
是的.我没去见你们前，你们本不会被释放
Yes. You were not to be released until I had come to see you.
看来基顿先生的律师，芬纳兰小姐...
It seems Mr.Keaton's attorney,Miss Finneran...
…过于有效率地促成了他的释放。
...was a little too effective in expediting his release.
再留着你们其他人就没有意义了
Holding the rest of you became a moot point.
- 那瑞德福特呢？  - 瑞德福特先生一无所知
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
苏斯先生很少长久用同一批人工作...
Mr.Soze rarely works with the same people for long...
...而他们从不知道是为谁工作
...and they never know who they're working for.
没有手下，就不会被出卖
One cannot be betrayed if one has no people.
你为什么告诉我们？
So, why are you telling us?
因为你们偷过苏斯先生，芬斯特先生。
Because you have stolen from Mr.Soze,Mr.Fenster.
你们所有人
All of you.
只因为你们不知道这一点，你们才活着
That you did not know it is the only reason you're still alive.
他觉得你们欠了他 你们要还债
He feels you owe him.You will repay your debt.
去他妈的债，草泥马，我们怎知道你是为苏斯工作？
Fuck the debt, and fuck you.How do we know you work for Soze?
我觉得这没太大关系，霍克内先生
I don't think that is very relevant.
你们五个要对索尔・伯格之死负责…
All five of you are responsible for the murder of Saul Berg...
…还有他的保镖
...and his bodyguards.
瑞德福特先生可以作证
Mr.Redfoot can testify to your involvement.
我们知道他会这么做的
We can see to it that he will.
- 你想说什么？  - 建议是这样的，先生们:
- What's your point? - The offer is this, gentlemen:
苏斯先生的主要兴趣
Mr.Soze's primary interest...
…是毒品
...is narcotics.
我们可以说，有一个阿根廷集团，数年来一直在跟他竞争
He has been competing, shall we say with a group of Argentineans for several years.
与苏斯先生竞争已让他们损失惨重
Competing with Mr.Soze has taken its toll.
这些阿根廷人正在商谈…
These Argentineans are negotiating the sale...
…一笔九千一百万元的可卡因买卖
...of $91 million in cocaine in three days time.
不用说，这次采购将复活他们已经式微的组织
Needless to say,this purchase will revitalize the diminishing strength of their organization.
苏斯先生想你们制止这次买卖
Mr.Soze would like you to stop the deal.
如果愿意，你们可以等买卖完成后动手
If you choose,you may wait until after the buy.
换手多少钱都是你们的
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
苏斯先生想你们上船，在船上销毁可卡因
Mr.Soze would like you to get to the boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
此后你们就不欠他债了
And then you will be free of your obligations to Mr.Soze.
给个好理由，教我现在不杀你
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't kill you right now.
苏斯先生给你们的礼物
A gift from Mr.Soze.
日安，先生们
Good day, gentlemen.
（芬斯特）
他们这里有我一生的资料，从我十八岁后干的每一件事
They got my whole life in here,everything I've done since I was 18.
他们他妈的什么都知道
They fuckin' know everything.
每一个跟我一起干过活或者坐过牢的人
Everybody I've ever worked with or did time with.
不
No.
- 这事不对劲   - 我不知道
- This isn't right. - I don't know.
纽约那个曾经说起过苏斯的人是谁？
Who's that guy who used to talk about Soze in New York?
- 布里克・马林  - 他为他做事，间接的
- Bricks Marlin. - He did jobs for him, indirect stuff.
他说他总是能得到超出他干的活五倍的钱
He said he always made five times more money on it than the job was worth.
那家伙只是个幻影
This guy's a pipe dream.
小林利用他作掩护
Kobayashi's using him
for window dressing.
我不知道，这不好
I don't know. This is bad.
都是鬼扯.这人可能是洛杉矶警察。这是他妈的圈套
It's bullshit. This guy could be LAPD.It's a fuckin' setup.
从我听说的来看，苏斯是那种屠夫杀人狂
The way I hear it,Soze's some kind of butcher.
- 是个变态无比的他妈的屠夫  - 没有凯撒・苏斯！
- A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher. - There is no Keyser Soze!
凯撒・苏斯是谁？
Who is Keyser Soze?
他应该是个土耳其人 有人说他父亲是德国人
He's supposed to be Turkish.Some say his father was German.
从没人相信他是真实存在的
Nobody ever believed he was real.
没有人认识他，或见过直接为他工作的人
Nobody knew him or saw anybody that ever worked directly for him.
按小林的说法，人人都可能为苏斯工作过
To hear Kobayashi tell it,anybody could have worked for Soze.
你无从得知。那就是他的厉害
You never knew. That was his power.
魔鬼耍过的最大的花招就是其令世人相信他不存在
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled was convincing the world he didn't exist.
这些伙计们告诉我的一个故事，我相信...
One story the guys told me,the story I believe...
...那是他在土耳其时发生的事
...was from his days in Turkey.
有一帮匈牙利人想要开山立柜，
There was a gang of Hungarians that wanted their own mob.
他们知道想有势力，并不需要用枪…
They realized that to be in power,you didn't need guns...
…金钱，甚至不需要人多
...or money or even numbers.
只需要有决心做其他人不敢做的事
You just needed the will to do what the other guy wouldn't.
不久，他们有了势力，赶上了苏斯
After a while they come into power,and then they come after Soze.
他当时规模小。只是经营毒品，他们说的。
He was small-time then.Just running dope, they say.
下午，他们闯进他家，要抢他的生意
They come to his home in the afternoon looking for his business.
他们在房子里找到他的妻儿，决定等苏斯回来
They find his wife and kids in the house,and decide to wait for Soze.
他回到家，发现妻子被强奸，孩子们在哭喊
He comes home to find his wife raped and children screaming.
匈牙利人知道苏斯凶狠，不是可以愚弄的
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough,not to be trifled with.
他们让他知道他们是冲着生意来的
They let him know they meant business.
不！
No!
他们说想要他的地盘，以及他所有的生意
They tell him they want his territory,all his business.
苏斯环顾家人的脸
Soze looks over the faces of his family.
然后向这些有决心的人展示什么是真正的决心
Then he showed these men of will what will really was.
他告诉他们他情愿看着家人死去…
He tells them he would rather see his family dead...
而不是此后继续偷生
...than live another day after this.
他放走最后那个匈牙利人…
He lets the last Hungarian go...
等妻儿入土后，追踪这班党徒逐一报复
...waits until his family is in the ground,and goes after the rest of the mob.
他杀了他们的孩子，杀了他们的妻子…
He kills their kids, he kills their wives...
…杀了他们的父母及其朋友
...he kills their parents and their friends.
烧掉他们的居所…
He burns down the houses they live in...
…及他们工作的店铺
...and the stores they work in.
他杀了那些欠他们钱的人。然后就像这样…
He kills people that owe them money.And like that...
…他消失了，转入地下
...he's gone, underground.
自此再没人见过他。他成了一个神话
Nobody's ever seen him since.He becomes a myth.
一个罪犯们晚上给孩子说的鬼故事
A spook story that criminals tell their kids at night.
“要是不听话，凯撒・苏斯就会来抓你”
"Rat on your pop,and Keyser Soze will get you."
没有人相信这事
No one ever really believes.
你相信有这人吗？
Do you believe in him?
基顿总是说:
Keaton always said:
“我不信上帝，但我怕他”
"I don't believe in God,but I'm afraid of him."
我信上帝
I believe in God.
唯一让我恐惧的就是凯撒・苏斯
And the only thing that scares me is Keyser Soze.
这你当回事吗？
You give any weight to this?
我可以给你介绍法院的丹・曼厮固
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser from Justice.
他有份苏斯在华盛顿的文件。这段时间已经成了他的爱好了。
He's got a file on Soze in DC.It's been a hobby of his for a while.
很多人视他为《无敌浩克》 中的那个记者
A lot of guys equate him to that reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
你听过他的事？
You've heard of him?
哪儿？道上？
Where? On the street?
有几次，你知道，外围传言
A few times. You know, outside stuff.
某人替某个为某个从苏斯那里拿钱的人工作。
Someone working for a guy who worked for a guy who got money from Soze.
那一类的屁话
Shit like that.
它可能是一种古老的标记，一种符印
It could be an old badge. A hex sign.
一个莫测的名字，会让人不敢搞你
Keep people from fucking with you when a name meant something.
- 但你来了   - 妈的，没错
- But you're here. - Shit, yeah.
这家伙想从医院里逃走，就因为害怕苏斯
This guy's trying to walk out of a hospital because he's so afraid of Soze.
我会探个虚实的
I'll run it up the flagpole.
我是清白的。事情怎样我就怎讲。
I came clean. I told it like it happened.
我怎么去的那儿又有什么关系？
So what about how I got there?
如果我的话满是漏洞，地方检察官早就告诉我别指望特赦了。
It's so full of holes, the DA would've told me to forget amnesty.
你想从我这知道的也得到了。又怎样。
You got what you wanted out of me.Big deal.
- 那就是你没告诉地方检察官的原因？  - 你说呢…
- That's why you never told the DA? - You tell me.
如果我告诉你是尼斯湖怪雇的我，你会怎么说？
If I told you the Loch Ness monster hired me, what would you say?
做污点证人，我们会召你作证
Turn state's evidence.We'll put you on the stand.
我已经豁免了。你还能给我开什么条件？
I've got immunity.What can you possibly offer me?
若真有凯撒・苏斯其人，他会来找你的
If there really is a Keyser Soze,he's gonna come lookin' for you.
你有没有大脑？
Where's your head?
你以为压力来自何方？
Where do you think the pressure is?
凯撒・苏斯，或者你怎么称呼他都行，知道我现在在哪
Keyser Soze, or whatever you call him,knows where I am right now.
他有办法捅你屁股，因此他十分钟内就能把我捞出去
He has the burner on your ass to let me go so he can scoop me up 10 minutes later.
豁免权也就是跟你们这些混球交易罢了
Immunity was just a deal with you assholes.
一旦我被保释出去，就有了新麻烦
I got a new problem when I post bail.
为何让他玩弄于股掌？我们能保护你
Why play into his hands?We can protect you.
多谢了，戴夫。到现在为止你干得很好。威逼利诱。
Thanks, Dave. Bang-up job so far.Extortion, coercion.
如果我要你舔我的屁股，请原谅。
Pardon me if I ask you to kiss my pucker.
整得我们走投无路的那群混蛋，正是现在保释我的人。
The same fuckers that rounded us up are now bailing me out?
去你的
Fuck you.
你以为你能逮住凯撒・苏斯？
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
你以为像他这样的人会让你接近，让你抓住，揪出他的脑袋来？
You think a guy like that comes this close to getting caught and sticks his head out?
若他真要来，那就是为了除掉我
If he comes up for anything,it'll be to get rid of me.
那以后…
After that...
…我的看法是你再也听不到他的消息了
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
后来怎样了？
What happened next?
第二天我们醒来，芬斯特已经走了
We woke up the next morning and Fenster was gone.
会被苏斯整垮的念头让他受不了
He couldn't handle the idea of slumming for Soze.
他留下字条祝我们好运…
He left us a note wishing us good luck...
…还拿走了大部分我们凑起来的钱
...and took a chunk of the money we'd scraped together.
然后怎样？
Then what?
麦克马纳斯很狂躁
McManus was furious.
他说要抓他回来扯出他的心。那一类的屁话。
He talked about tracking him down and ripping his heart out. All sorts of shit.
那天晚上，我们接到那个电话
That night, we got the call.
什么电话？
What call?
小林告诉我们哪里能找到芬斯特
Kobayashi told us where we could find Fenster.
我们快他妈的离开这儿
Let's get the fuck out of here.
我们得把他埋了
We gotta bury him.
用什么？
With what?
用我们的手
With our hands.
这是发神经
This is nuts.
这是他妈的干沙
It's dry fucking sand.
等他腐烂时 那些冲浪者一里外也能闻到
When he rots the surfers
are gonna smell him a mile away.
- 挖，你他妈的  - 我们该怎么办？
- Dig, you fuck. - What are we gonna do?
这家伙会他妈杀了我们
This fuckin' guy is gonna kill us.
我不知道你，拐脚，但我能跑。这我没问题
I don't know about you, peg leg,but I can run. I got no problem with that.
看起来小林对此也没什么问题
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have a problem with it either.
你跑了，我们就要为你挖一个坑
You run, and we're gonna be diggin' a hole for you.
你明白吗？
You got that?
我们埋的又不是我亲儿子。我不欠任何人的！
This ain't my boy we're burying.I don't owe anybody!
- 去你的吧  - 他跟我搭档五年了
- So fuck you. - He was my partner for five years.
我们干过的活、我见过的钱比你想象的还多
We did more jobs and I saw more money than you can ever count.
你他妈去死！
So fuck you!
- 所以现在才要还债！  - 这不是还债！
- 'Cause now it's payback! - It's not payback!
这只是警告
It's precaution.
你想还债？你想跑路？我不在乎
You want payback? You wanna run?I don't care.
我不是为芬斯特做
I'm not doin' this for Fenster.
也不是为你们做
I'm not doin' it for you.
我只是为我自己做
I'm doin' this for me.
我要了结这事
I'm gonna finish this thing.
我不会让这叫小林的杂种活下去
This Kobayashi bastard is not gonna stand on me.
芬斯特被杀后，没有人逃跑？
After they killed Fenster,nobody would run?
- 我想的，我想我们能逃脱   - 那你怎么不说？
- I wanted to. I thought we could make it. - Why didn't you say anything?
相信我，我试了， 但基顿不同意这么做
Believe me, I tried,but Keaton wouldn't have it.
对他来说太牵强
It was too far-fetched for him.
基顿是个脚踏实地的人，前警察
Keaton was a grounded guy. An ex-cop.
对于警察来说，从来没有复杂的解释
To a cop, the explanation is never that complicated.
总是很简单
It's always simple.
道上的传说不是真的，幕后黑手不存在
There's no mystery to the street,no arch-criminal.
你看见具尸体，心想是他兄弟干的。可能真就是。
You got a body and think his brother did it, you're probably right.
没人与基顿争论
Nobody argued with Keaton.
他们下决心打败小林
They just set their minds to whacking Kobayashi.
他们上来了
They're coming up.
- 听到了吗？他上来了  - 他正下来
- Did you hear me? He's coming up. - He's on his way down.
别动
Don't move.
按二十楼，马上
Press 20. Do it now.
出去
Move.
- 我们的答复是“不行”   - 苏斯先生会很--
- The answer is "no." - Mr.Soze will be most--
听着，混蛋 根本没有凯撒・苏斯这个人
Listen, cocksucker,there is no Keyser Soze.
要再提这名字，我立刻就杀了你
Mention his name again,I'll kill you right now.
真是奇怪的威胁，我以为你们来这里怎么都要杀了我
A strange threat. I assume you've come here to kill me anyway.
我知道你找得到我们…
We know that you can get to us...
…可现在你也知道了 我们能找到你
...but now you know that we can get to you.
我最后给你次机会去终止此事
I'm giving you one last chance to call this off.
我的雇主已经下了决心
My employer has made up his mind.
- 他不会改变主意的   - 我们也不会
- He does not change it. - Neither do we.
你杀了芬斯特， 但你杀不了我们所有人
You got Fenster,but you won't be able to get all of us.
至少在我们中的某个干掉你之前不会
Not before one of us gets through to you.
我信你的话，真心实意地信
I believe you. I most sincerely do.
若你们不是有能耐的人， 就不会被选中
You would not have been chosen were you not so suitable.
但我不能做这决定。无论你们拿什么来威胁我…
But I cannot make this decision.Whatever you threaten me with is...
…跟我不能完全执行命令而遭到的惩罚
...ludicrous in comparison to what will be done to me...
…比起来都是小菜一碟
...if I do not carry out my orders in full.
我就是要杀你的人
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
我只想你知道那点
I just wanted you to know that.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我恳求你，相信我
I implore you, believe me...
… 苏斯先生确有其人
...Mr.Soze is very real...
- …而他是个很坚决的人   - 我们等着瞧吧
- ...and very determined. - We'll see.
在你干掉我之前…
Before you do me in...
…你们会允许我先去了结与芬纳兰小姐的公事，对吧？
...you will let me finish my business with Miss Finneran first, won't you?
你说什么？
What did you say?
伊迪・芬纳兰
Edie Finneran.
她正在楼上我的办公室…
She's upstairs in my office...
…等着交涉一桩引渡案
...for an extradition deposition.
我要求她亲自来谈这案子
I requested she be
put on the case personally.
她是昨天飞来的
She flew in yesterday.
没关系
No matter.
杀了我吧
Kill away.
你在说谎
You're lying.
是吗？
Am I?
芬纳兰小姐在洛杉矶期间有人陪护
Miss Finneran's escort while she's here in Los Angeles.
片刻不离
Never leaves her for a moment.
我想你会高兴有好手保护着她
I thought you'd be glad to know she's in good hands.
休息会儿吧 船在星期五到
Get some rest.The boat will be ready for you on Friday.
如果在那之前我见到你或你的朋友
If I see you or any of your friends before then...
…芬纳兰小姐死前会遭受最可怕的污辱
...Miss Finneran will be the victim of a most gruesome violation before she dies.
你的父亲也一样，霍克内先生…
As indeed will your father, Mr.Hockney...
…还有你亚利桑那州的叔叔兰道尔，肯特先生
...and your Uncle Randall in Arizona,Mr.Kint.
我可能只会阉掉麦克马纳斯先生的侄子，戴维。
I might only castrate Mr.McManus' nephew, David.
我说得够清楚了吗？
Do I make myself clear?
我们会处理楼下那两具尸体
We will take care of the two bodies downstairs.
并会把账算到芬斯特先生身上
We'll add them to the cost of Mr.Fenster.
请恕失陪，先生们
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
非常难安排
It's a logistical nightmare.
近距离，10到20个人
Close quarters. 10, maybe 20 men.
不知道甲板下还有多少人
There's no tellin' how many more are gonna be below deck.
我们能偷袭那些家伙吗？
Can we stealth these guys?
有那么多可卡因，他们会小心防范的
With all that coke, they're gonna be ready.
这带给我们另一个问题
Which brings me to sunny point Number 2.
即使我们有人能杀进去并劫走那船 还是什么也得不到
Even if one of us gets through and jacks the boat, we still got nothin'.
等他们收了钱呢？
What if we wait for the money?
那至少又多了十个人
Ten more men at least.
依我看，干不了
In my opinion, it can't be done.
谁进去了都不会活着出来
Anyone who goes in is not comin' out alive.
- 我会等钱到再下手  - 我也是
- I'm gonna wait for the money. - Me, too.
- 你们听见他刚才的话吗？  - 反正必须去，我得拿一份
- Did you hear what he just said? - If I'm goin' in, I want a cut.
我也是
Me, too.
没有办不成的事
There's nothing that can't be done.
我简直不敢相信，我们就这么去送死
I just can't believe we're gonna walk in to certain death.
电台里说纽约正在下雨
The news said it's raining in New York.
那是什么语言？
What language is that?
不知道。俄语，我想
I don't know. Russian, I think.
匈牙利语
Hungarian?
包裹到了，先生们
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
小子们准备好了吗？
You kids ready?
若不是停下来答你 就已经预备好了
I would be if I didn't have to stop and answer you.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
麦克马纳斯，你最好在十秒内到位
McManus, you better be set up in 10 seconds.
我好了
I'm ready.
我要你留在这里
I want you to stay here.
我本来要掩护--
I'm supposed to cover--
如果我们出不来了，带上钱走
If we don't get out of this,take the money and go.
我不能--
I can't--
去找伊迪 把事情全都告诉她
Find Edie.Tell her everything that happened.
她认识许多人 她知道该如何处理
She knows people. She knows what to do.
如果用我的方法除不掉小林，那么她有她的办法做到
If I don't get Kobayashi my way,she'll get him her way.
- 可要是我--   - 按我说的去做
- What if I-- - Just do what I say.
拜托了
Please.
告诉她….
Tell her that...
告诉她我已经尽力了
Tell her I tried.
麦克马纳斯，他过来了
McManus, he's on his way.
我已经就位
I'm there.
一，二，三，四…
One, two, three, four...
…五，六，七…
...five, six, seven...
奥斯瓦德的活不好干啊
Oswald was a fag.
你好
Hi.
你好吗？
How you doin'?
有什么问题吗？
Is there a problem?
好了
Now.
麦克唐纳先生有块地
"Old McDonald had a farm
伊呀，伊呀，哟
"Ee-aye, ee-aye, O
“在那地里他杀了班人”
"And on that farm, he shot some guys"
猫王要出场了
Elvis has left the building.
别开枪，别开枪.自己人
Hold fire. Hold fire. Vamonos!
你好
Hello.
你为何不逃？
Why didn't you run?
我被吓呆了
I froze up.
我想起了芬斯特，他被埋葬时的样子
I thought about Fenster and how he looked when we buried him.
然后我又想到基顿，那时候看起来他可能圆满完成
Then I thought about Keaton,and it looked like he might pull it off.
今天有个男孩在沙滩上发现一具尸体
A boy found a body on the beach today.
是被人从船上抛下海的 头部中两枪
Thrown clear of the boat.Shot twice in the head.
局里的两个人去鉴定了他的身份
Two guys from the Bureau identified him.
- 还有呢？  - 他叫阿图罗・马克兹
- What else? - His name was Arturo Marquez.
是个阿根廷小走私犯
A petty smuggler from Argentina.
去年在纽约曾因毒品交易被捕
He was arrested last year in New York for trafficking.
他逃往加州，但在长滩被捉回
He escapes to California.They pick him up in Long Beach.
他们安排引渡他 他又逃了
They're setting up extradition,he escapes again.
重点来了
Now, get this.
伊迪・芬纳兰提出的引渡建议
Edie Finneran's brought in to advise on the proceedings.
小林
Kobayashi.
纽约传给了我一份他的证词
New York faxed me a copy of his testimony.
- 他是个告密者  - 是个他妈的大叛徒
- He was a rat. - A big fucking rat.
阿图罗很害怕回到监狱
Arturo was very opposed to returning to prison.
甚至于他供出了将近五十个人
So much so,that he named close to 50 people.
猜猜最后的人名是谁？
Guess who he named in the finale.
凯撒・苏斯
Keyser Soze.
还有
There's more.
我把所知一切告诉你 若说重覆了就告诉我
I'll tell you what I know.Stop me when this sounds familiar.
船上根本就没有毒品
There was no dope on that boat.
你待着别出声
You, stay quiet.
他来了
He's here.
我知道他来了，就是他 我告诉你，就是他
I know he's here. That's him.I'm telling you, that's him.
我知道他来了！
I know he's here!
- 你不明白.是他   - 闭嘴
- You can't understand. That's him. - Shut up.
就是他，你听到没？ 我告诉你，是凯撒・苏斯！
That's him. You hear me?I'm telling you, it's Keyser Soze!
-  霍克内在哪里？  - 我不知道
- Where's Hockney? - I don't know.
这儿没可卡因
There's no coke.
- 什么？  - 你听得很清楚，该死的
- What? - You heard me, dumb fuck.
- 没有可卡因！  - 妈的？没有毒品？
- There's no coke! - What the fuck? No coke?
我上上下下搜过他妈的每个房间
I've been up and down in every fucking room.
- 一定有可卡因！  - 什么也没有！
- There's gotta be coke! - There is nothing!
没有！
Nothing!
你不要跟我耍花样了
Don't you fuck with me.
没有他妈的可卡因！
There is no fucking coke!
我要出去了
I'm out of here.
我什么都没对他们说
I told them nothing.
我发誓
I swear.
我什么也没跟他们说，求你了
I told them nothing. Please.
他妈的是怎么回事？
What the fuck is goin' on?
这是真是太怪了
The strangest thing.
那就是你说的。你看见一个穿西服的瘦男人？
That's what you said.You saw a man in a suit with a slim build.
等等
Wait a minute.
你是说你看见了凯撒・苏斯？
Are you saying you saw Keyser Soze?
- 你先前说不知道那是谁  - 我知道船上有毒品
- You said you didn't know who it was. - I know there was dope on that boat.
- 别再拖延时间  - 我没有
- Stop stallin'. - I'm not.
- 你明白我指的是什么  - 从我面前消失
- You know what I'm getting at. - Get out of my face.
我已经被豁免了 不需要遭这罪
I got immunity. I don't have to take this.
你明白我指的是什么
You know what I'm getting at.
- 我不知道你在说什么  - 真相！
- I don't know what you're talking about. - The truth!
想告诉我你看见有人杀了基顿
Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
我看见了
I did.
你在对我撒谎
You're lying to me.
- 你一直都知道  - 我不知道你在说什么
- You've known this whole time. - I don't know what you're saying.
我看见基顿中了枪，我跟你发誓
I did see Keaton get shot. I swear to you.
你为什么不救他？你有枪
Why didn't you help him? You had a gun.
他是你的朋友
He was your friend.
因为我害怕
Because I was afraid.
- 害怕  - 怕什么？
- Afraid. - Afraid of what?
- 怕什么--   - 我知道那是凯撒・苏斯
- Afraid of--  - I knew it was Keyser Soze.
是凯撒・苏斯，就是魔鬼本尊
It was Keyser Soze, I mean,the Devil himself.
你怎么能在魔鬼背后开枪？
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
要是射不中呢？
What if you miss?
那说回码头的事
Let's get back to the pier.
- 阿图罗・马克兹。听说过他吗？  - 什么？没有
- Arturo Marquez. Ever hear of him? - What? No.
他是司法部的告密人
He was a stool pigeon for the Justice Department.
他向联邦司法官录了份口供
He swore out a statement to federal marshals...
…说他见过并能明确认出…
...saying that he had seen and could positively identify one...
凯撒・苏斯
...Keyser Soze.
报告这里还写着
It says right here in the report.
他熟知凯撒・苏斯的一切业务，包括…
He had intimate knowledge of his businesses, including...
...但不限于运毒及谋杀
...but not exclusive to,drug trafficking and murder.
我从未听说过他
I never heard of him.
他自己的人把他出卖给匈牙利帮
His own people were selling him to a gang of Hungarians.
最有可能是那帮苏斯在土耳其清除了的匈牙利人
Most likely the same Hungarians that Soze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
那钱并不是用来买毒品的
The money wasn't there for dope.
匈牙利人本打算购买…
The Hungarians were going to buy the one guy...
这唯一能把凯撒・苏斯定罪的人
...that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
- 我说了我从未听过他  - 但基顿听过
- I said I never heard of him. - But Keaton did.
伊迪・芬纳兰是马克兹引渡案的顾问
Edie Finneran was Marquez's extradition advisor.
她知道他是谁，以及他知道些什么
She knew who he was and what he knew.
船上根本没有毒品 这是一次袭击行动
There were no drugs on that boat.It was a hit.
一次自杀式行动，目的是干掉...
A suicide mission to whack out the one guy...
…这个能指证凯撒・苏斯的家伙
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
于是 苏斯派了些贼去干
So Soze put some thieves to it...
他知道能把这帮人置于死地
...men he knew he could march into certain death.
你说苏斯利用我们去杀人？
You're saying Soze sent us to kill someone?
我说是基顿干的，他把你留在后面是有原因的
I'm saying Keaton did.He left you behind for a reason.
按我说的去做
Just do what I tell you.
既然你们知道无论跑到哪，苏斯都能找到你…
If you all knew that Soze could find you anywhere...
…他为何还给你钱逃亡？
...why did he give you the money to run?
- 在船上你还能帮他   - 他想我活下去
- He could have used you on the boat. - He wanted me to live.
一个过去的贪污警察，毫无忠诚的心里...
A one-time dirty cop without a loyalty in the world...
…竟然会想挽救一个一文不值的残废鼠辈？
...finds it in his heart to save a worthless rat cripple?
不，先生。原因何在？
No, sir. Why?
伊迪
Edie.
我一分钟都没信过这个改过自新的故事
I don't buy that reform story for a minute.
就算我信…
Even if I did...
…我也不会相信他会派你去保护她
...I certainly don't believe he would send you to protect her.
那么为什么？
So why?
因为他是我的朋友
Because he was my friend.
不，他不是你的朋友 基顿没有朋友
No, he wasn't your friend.Keaton didn't have friends.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
他留下你的命 是因为他想这样做
He saved you because he wanted it that way.
这是他的意愿
It was his will.
- 基顿就是凯撒・苏斯  - 不是
- Keaton was Keyser Soze. - No.
能反对霍克内和麦克马纳斯这种人的意愿
A man who could wrangle the wills of men like Hockney and McManus.
能通过警局里多年的关系安排指认
A man who could engineer a police lineup through all his years of contacts in NYPD.
这样的人才会杀害伊迪・芬纳兰
The kind of man who could've killed Edie Finneran.
她昨天在宾夕法尼亚州一间酒店被发现
She was found yesterday at a hotel in Pennsylvania...
…头部中两枪
...shot twice in the head.
现在你对基顿有何看法？
What do you think about Keaton now?
伊迪？
Edie?
他利用你们让他上船
He used all of you to get him on that boat.
他一个人做不了。他必须亲自扣动扳机…
He couldn't get on alone.He had to pull the trigger himself...
…以确保干掉的正是那个…
...to make sure he got his man...
…能指认他的家伙
...the one man that could identify him.
全是胡说
This is all bullshit.
你说你看见他死了
You said you saw him die.
你有吗？
Or did you?
听到警车来到时，你必须藏起来
You had to hide when you heard the police cars.
你说在起火前听到枪声…
You said you heard the shot before the fire...
…可你没看见他死
...but you didn't see him die.
- 我了解他，他绝不会--    - 他控制了你
- I knew him. He would never-- - He programmed you.
他控制你告诉我们他想要你说的话
He programmed you to tell us what he wanted you to.
他知道我们逼近他了。你自己说的
He knew we were close.You said it yourself.
保护你的政治压力由何而来？
Where was the political pressure to protect you from?
就是基顿
It was Keaton.
- 被豁免是给你的奖赏   - 但为什么找我？
- Immunity was your reward. - But why me?
为什么不是芬斯特，或是麦克马纳斯和霍克内？
Why not Fenster or McManus or Hockney?
为什么是我？我又蠢又跛，为什么是我？
Why me? I'm stupid.I'm a cripple. Why me?
因为你跛
Because you're a cripple.
因为你蠢
Because you're stupid.
因为你比他们弱
Because you're weaker than them.
要是他死了….
If he's dead...
要是你说的是真的，那就没什么关系
If what you say is true,then it won't matter.
袭击出租车是他的主意，对吗？
It was his idea to hit the taxi service,wasn't it?
- 好了，跟我说实话   - 全是基顿
- Come on, tell me the truth. - It was all Keaton.
从一开始我们就跟从他
We followed him from the beginning.
我原先不知道
I didn't know.
我看到他死了
I saw him die.
我相信他已经死了。基督。
I believe he's dead. Christ.
你一个人不安全
You're not safe on your own.
你认为他是….
You think he's...
凯撒・苏斯？
Keyser Soze?
我不知道
I don't know.
凯撒・苏斯只是个挡箭牌，或者象你说的，是个鬼故事
Keyser Soze's a shield,or like you said, a spook story.
但我了解基顿，有人在外面勒紧绳索等着你
But I know Keaton, and someone is out there pulling strings for you.
- 待在这，让我们保护你   - 我不当诱饵，我今天获释了
- Stay here and let us protect you. - I'm not bait. I post today.
二十分钟前你就获释了
You posted 20 minutes ago.
里奥探长要你离开这里
Capt. Leo wants you out of here.
- 除非你转做政府证人   - 我愿意碰碰运气，谢了
- Unless you turn state's. - I'll take my chances.
如果有人想要干掉你，那他们会在外面下手
If someone wants to get you,they're gonna get you out there.
转做证人，你可能都不会见到审讯
Turn state's evidence.You might never see trial.
也许是这样
Maybe so.
但我不是告密的人
But I'm not a rat.
他妈的条子
Fuckin' cops.
对不起，能用下你们的传真机吗？
Excuse me, can I use your fax machine?
你得在这儿签名，肯特先生
You'll have to sign for these, Mr.Kint.
一块表，金的
One watch, gold.
一个打火机，金的
One cigarette lighter, gold.
一包烟，谢谢
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
我们仍然一无所获
We still got nothing.
我知道了我想了解的，关于基顿
I know what I wanted to know about Keaton.
那还是什么都没有
Which is nothing.
没关系，他会知道我们多么接近他了
No matter.He'll have to know how close we came.
不管有没有凯撒・苏斯
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
…只要基顿还活着，他就再不会出现了
...if Keaton is alive,he's not comin' up again.
我会找到他
I'll find him.
浪费时间
Waste of time.
传闻不平息就不是传闻了
A rumor's not a rumor that doesn't die.
什么？
What?
没什么
Nothing.
伙计，你真懒
Man, you're a slob.
可这些东西自有条理
But it all has a system.
如果你看对的话就顺了。你得退后点看。
It all makes sense if you look at it right.You gotta stand back from it.
要看真正恐怖的地方吗？ 看看我的车库
You wanna see a real horror show?See my garage.
（通缉）
说服我，告诉我每个细节
Convince me. Tell me every last...
我曾经加入过在伊利诺州邵崎市 的一个男声四重唱组合…
When I was in that barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
- 你到底有没有大脑？  - 我们需要思考，回想
- Where's your head? - We need to think, think back.
我肯定你们已听过不少传言
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
- 布里克・马林  - 这事不对劲
- Bricks Marlin. - This isn't right.
- 我想听听你的故事  - 都在那儿
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
- 我直话直说   - 来自加州的，名叫瑞德福特
- I'm tellin' it straight. - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
- 这是苏斯先生送上的礼物  - 老实对我说
- A gift from Mr.Soze. - Talk to me.
- 那瑞德福特呢？  - 瑞德福特先生并不知情
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
- 利用不知情的人…  - 是个大胖子。象逆戟鲸
- Using pawns... - A big fat guy. Like, orca fat.
有个律师…
There was a lawyer...
小林
Kobayashi...
我在危地马拉摘咖啡豆时，做过新鲜咖啡
When I was picking beans in Guatemala we made fresh coffee.
- 我知道你认为他是好人  - 我知道他很好
- I know you thought he was a good man. - I know he was good.
- 告诉我全部的细节   - 这事怪极了
- You tell me every last detail. - The strangest thing.
你怎么能在魔鬼的背后开枪？
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
这家伙受到高层黑暗势力的保护
This guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of...
说说你的故事，拐脚佬
What's your story, pretzel man?
- 还有个律师  - 什么律师？
- There was a lawyer. - What lawyer?
我就是小林
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
- 小林，小林，  - 告诉我所有的细节
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi.  - Tell me every last detail.
-我为凯撒・苏斯做事， -说服我，说服我
- I work for Keyser Soze.- Convince me. Convince me.
所有街头混混和人渣
Every creep and scumbag that works the street...
…都会知道话痨・肯特的大名
...will know the name of Verbal Kint.
那跛子，你看见他吗？
The cripple, did you see him?
- 那跛子！他朝哪里走了？  - 他往那边去了
- The cripple! Which way did he go? - He went out that way.
我知道你知道点什么， 我还知道你没说实话…
I know you know something.I know you're not telling...
我比你聪明
I'm smarter than you...
…不管你是否愿意， 我都会找到我要的答案
...and I'm gonna find out whether you like it or not.
对警察来说，解释从来不复杂
To a cop, the explanation is never complicated.
- 总是很简单  - 真相
- It's always simple. - The truth!
根本就没什么幕手主使
There's no arch-criminal behind it all.
实权人物，有能力…
Somebody with power,somebody who is capable...
凯撒・苏斯
Keyser Soze!
你以为像他这样的人会让你接近，让你抓住，揪出他的脑袋来？
You think a guy like that gets this close to getting caught and sticks his head out?
因为你蠢，因为你跛
Because you're stupid.Because you're a cripple.
现在我想知道的，那跛子是谁？
What I wanna know is, who's the gimp?
你一直都知道
You've known the whole fuckin' time.
他来也是要找我。我肯定基顿已经死了
If he comes up for anything it'll be for me. I'm sure Keaton is dead.
我的双腿没有知觉，凯撒
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
干这行我学会的第一件事，你知道是什么？
First thing I learned on the job.You know what?
- 就是如何辨认凶手   - 你见到那个跛子了吗？
- How to spot a murderer.- You got the cripple in there?
- 他有提到凯撒・苏斯吗？  - 谁？
- Did he mention Keyser Soze?- Who?
那之后…
After that...
…我的看法是你再听不到他的消息了
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
魔鬼耍过的最大的花招就是其令世人相信他不存在
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled was convincing the world he didn't exist.
然后就像那样…
And like that...
…他消失了
...he's gone.